Imagine a world where you could take
comments on your content
and turn them into clients. Well that,
ladies and gentlemen, is
now a real... I can't talk like that,
is a reality.
I'm going to show you some of the stuff
that usually I would only show people if
they were paying me money.
But the thought is,
you could end up seeing this and
learning so much from it,
that you end up paying me money.
So over here we have ManyChat.
I've been using ManyChat since about 2017,
and although some of the rules have
changed,
how it integrates with Facebook
and whatnot, I still think it's a very
powerful tool.
I do not even use this to its full
potential.
Over here, if we click on Automation,
because that's really where I think the
power
of chatbots are,
to be doing work for you whilst you're
asleep or doing other
things.
And here you can see a list of some of the
automations I've been
using. So very quickly, an automation
is some kind of process that we can put in
place so that when someone on our social
media, whether it be Facebook or whether
it be Instagram, because ManyChat
is a partner of Meta, they're the only two
that we can properly use at the moment.
On a certain behavior,
we can get a prompt, a response,
a message.
So for instance,
if I click New Automation up here,
start from scratch.
I know this can look very complex in the
beginning.
Wow, so refreshing. Product placement.
Love that. So New Trigger.
A trigger is the thing that's going to
happen for that response.
Thing that happens, response. Now
when you see this, straight away,
any of you
that aren't using this,
your eyes just light up.
So whether or not someone comments on a
post or a reel, replies to our story,
sends
a message, comments on a live,
we can send them a message.
I had great success with this recently for
one of my last challenges that we did,
where I would go live,
and I would make the title of the live,
Comment the Word
Challenge.
So people would comment the word challenge
on the live, and it meant
they could stay concurrently watching the
live video I was doing.
Then after that,
they could go to their inbox as to where
they would find the
message. Now before we get carried away,
it's worth noting that if someone DMs
us a message, we have more options,
but we'll get onto that in a second.
So we want someone to comment on our post
or reel.
A lot of people seem to think
that they are manually responding to
these, but
they're not. Some people might,
most of them aren't.
So I can pick a specific reel from here,
but these have already been posted,
so that's not ideal. So it's better
if we can look at all posts or reels, or
next post and reel. Now if you
were going to run a campaign,
say up until this
week,
if you commented the word calculator on
any of my posts on Instagram,
you would get a DM saying, "Hey,
you want to use my calorie calculator?
Here it is." Which is a squeeze page,
it's a lead magnet.
I let people use the calorie calculator
for free, but then if they want a more
detailed breakdown of all the information
I've given them, they have to give us
their email address. We have that
and have had that passively collect email
addresses for nearly a decade. So
if there's a generalized word,
there's not many
people that are going to be using
or messaging the word calculator to me
that
don't want a calorie calculator.
So for me, I would have used that.
However,
if you're running a novel campaign,
you might just say, "Hey,
for the next post and reel,
continue." Now there are two options here.
You can get them to put in a keyword,
or sometimes you can do any comment,
and this
is really where I'm dropping my pants
and explaining some of my marketing nous.
Sometimes you put the keyword
and the first one I ever used was,
comment the word
daddy. People are like, "Oh,
that's a bit inappropriate." Made it a bit
funny, a
bit jovial. But actually,
in my last successful chatbot
automation, I said, "Any comment,"
and in the video, I said, "Comment your
favorite sex position." So
that people were putting some of the
craziest
sexual positions ever, wondering, wow,
is there going to be a chatbot response to
me saying reverse cowgirl? So then I
was getting interactions from
people that just kind of wanted to see
what happened.
So the any comment one's quite good.
Specific keyword,
let's say I'm using the word challenge.
I'd put the word challenge,
but I'd also put the word challenge spelt
wrong,
just in case someone is retarded.
So let's say I'm doing January
kickoff challenge, whatever.
I've got those two things there, cool.
That's my triggers. I'm happy with it.
Continue.
Now you can send random multiple replies,
like, "Thanks,
mate. Cheers,
bro." I'm not a big fan of them,
if I'm honest.
I've used them before, but
if you've got 300 comments on a post,
you reply to all
of them,
they're thinking this person's got too
much spare time.
Now,
we need something that's logically going
to happen
after this.
So we've got the trigger set up,
next post or reel, the word challenge.
Now because this is an Instagram
automation,
we're going to want an Instagram
message. Now this is it. You go, "Wow,
thank you, brother.
For more information about the challenge,
just click
that sexy button below. All the best, Big
Sexy."
Then Add Button,
want to change the button to Challenge
Info. For any of you on Mac,
did you know that if you hit Control,
Command, and
Space Bar, you get your emojis? If you
didn't, you do now. You do now. Cool.
We want to open website,
and I actually have... Look at that.
See that? What,
you don't have keyboard shortcuts set up
so that I type in
challenge one,
got the URL for my challenge. What's that?
Email auto.
There's a short link for one of my
autoresponders.
What's that? JSA 2,
my business partner's email address.
I've got shortcuts for everything,
brother.
What do you need?
I've got a shortcut for it. Where were we?
Bersh.
So now you might want to think, oh,
what you say?
Oh, I didn't put something there. My bad.
My bad. Challenge info.
Got a bit carried away showing off there,
didn't I?
So that's all looking nice and good,
and you're probably thinking,
what does that look like? Not a problem.
Go up here to preview.
Bersh. Wow. That's so good.
You can even click that to
check the efficacy. Look at that.
Fantastic.
Fantastic. What a place.
What a time to be alive.
So then we can set that live.
Straight away, you can then post your next
post and start.
You can do it in the caption.
I like doing it in the video.
And you can just say it subtly. Oh,
and by the way, if you wanted to know more
about that challenge,
you can just comment the word challenge.
Anyway, back to the point. Boom,
you're in, you're out.
So then people that
are interested can be actionable on it,
and people that aren't,
aren't.
Is that it? No.
We're just getting warmed up.
We've just got you moist.
It's now time to get stuck in.
You can tell I enjoy this stuff.
By the way, guys, just to let you know,
here, this is where I'm going to spend the
rest of my morning, in The Minuteship,
helping people. It's how I make money.
I work with small brands, businesses,
some personal trainers, a lot.
There'll be a link in the description.
But let's get back to it before we get
distracted.
Let's make a daddy automation. Something-
Sexy.
New trigger.
I want someone to send me a message. Why?
Because we have more options with this,
and I'll explain.
Select a way to trigger the automation.
Detect specific words. Daddy.
Let's just put it. So, new trigger. So,
I'm already doing this, sorry.
Keyword trigger created. Now,
we're going to drop this person a message,
but we're
going to take this to the next level.
"Hey mate, thanks for the DM." Oh,
what's that? Delay. Wait a few seconds.
Make it seem like I'm really there. Text.
"Sorry, bear with." One sec. Delay.
"So basically,
I really wanted the opportunity to tell
you more
about my 12-week challenge." Delay.
"If you're someone looking to drop a bit
of timber
and remain accountable,
this would be perfect for you." And
again, this could be anything.
This could be tax accounting.
I choose this because I've run a PT
business for a while.
Then after a while,
you go up here to preview.
"Thanks for the DM." Oh.
Oh my God,
he's actually messaging me back.
"Sorry, bear with." [chuckles] Yeah,
I'll wait.
Oh, my God, is that the James Smith?
"So basically,
I really wanted the opportunity..." Oh.
"Tell me more." And we can make this as
long as we want.
We could put an image in. Let's say
a thumbnail. Do you like this thumbnail?
I made it myself.
Oh. And then we could put another delay.
Then we could put,
what else have we got in here?
Audio, send a voice note, share a video.
So this is where things can get really
interesting. Even here.
I put a little audio file in there.
We could then say, "Hey mate, sorry,
just on
the move. Basically,
wanted to tell you more about the program.
How was that voice note?
Did I make it clear?
The next thing ideally would be to book in
a call with the sales team,
if you're happy to." What else have we got
here?
Gallery, card, video.
So I did one of these recently.
Let's have a look how this looks now.
The little delays.
Sometimes you can make the delays up to 60
seconds, which really makes it
look like you're there. Now,
something else you can do with this is you
can make people know
that it's an automation,
and they're not too bothered because
it's still quite cool.
You're getting a message from someone,
and you can take
people on a little journey.
There can be other...
Sometimes you can get to the end of it.
Sometimes they need to respond to get to
it.
So here, you see, choose next step,
condition. These are the complex things.
Sometimes it goes like, "What
are you looking to do?" Then they respond,
then they
get the next sequence.
Some of these go really complex,
but I don't think we really
need to worry about that too much.
But let's think about what kind of
campaign are we going to be running here.
So let me delete this one.
I don't think it's
the best idea to use this just to try
and get someone to buy,
because even one of
my most previous videos telling you to not
go to a website is exactly for this
reason. So new trigger.
Let's maybe even just go,
someone sends you a
message, emails. Yep, sweet. That's there.
"Thank you so much for the DM. Basically,
I really want to change your life."
Cool. Little delay, bit of text.
"Each day over the next 100
days,
I'm going to send you an email that's
going to
revolutionize your understanding of
fitness.
Now,
I know you may not think these would be
that good, but they're completely free,
and if you don't
absolutely love them,
you can unsubscribe at any point.
So would you please do me the favor
and sign up
today? I'm positive you are."
Then my good delay, text. Oh, yeah.
"Please use this link." Let's have a look
how that looks.
"Thank you so much for... And basically,
I really want to change your life." Wow.
"Each day over the next 100 days,
I'm going to send you an email that's
going to
revolutionize your understanding of
fitness.
Now, I know..." See,
that delay should've been longer.
"Now, I know you may not think
that these are going to be good,
but you can
unsubscribe at any point.
So would you please do me the favor
and sign up today?
Oh, yeah, please use this link." Oh,
that is not working as a
hyperlink, is it? That's good
that we've discovered this.
Wow, I wonder why that is.
I wonder why that is, mate.
Okay, we're going to cut that. Add button.
This is why you've got to test your shit,
mate.
That's why you've got to test your shit.
Click here. Cool.
And then let's go a little finger point
just to let them know just in case
they're blind,
just in case their walking stick has
fallen on the floor.
And these don't take long. Basically,
this means that you can now put out really
engaging viral content onto the internet,
and people will arrive in your DMs.
And then they'll get these DM automations,
and you'll wake up with people in your
inbox. So that is just the dream, right?
Click here.
Where's it taking me? Oh my God,
look at this fantastic squeeze page.
Now, let me show you this in action,
actually.
So AWeber is one of my email lists.
Then if we go here, so I'm
not proactively getting people to join
this.
Here, you can actually see
that I turned the chatbot off.
So I turned it off to have a look whether
or not it was having a real impact on the
list.
But these email sign-ups every day
are coming from a
chatbot that I put on Facebook
that anytime someone comments,
it just slides into
their DMs and goes, "Hey,
I send emails every day.
They could really help you." And
that has been growing the list.
Not by a huge amount, to be honest,
because I'm not really using this list at
the
moment, but you get the idea.
So then you can just put out content.
And then off the back of it,
people can sign up to your email
newsletter passively.
And all you need to do
is just mention it in your content,
or you can set something
up so that anyone that comments gets
that DM.
Makes your life easier,
whether you're running campaigns,
selling something.
You could even say to people, "Hey,
I'm running a discount.
DM me the word." And just taking them on
that little journey can make your life
easier.
That's what we use these things for.
This is like a little mini employee just
sat there in the back end,
making your life easier.
How you're going to implement chatbots
into your business,
I don't know, but I hope that
was a detailed
walkthrough. I hope you enjoyed it.
This video is quite good, actually.
So to all of you lot in the mentorship,
I think I'm going to put this one in the
mentorship with the other chatbot
tutorials because it was quite good.
Link's in the description.
I hope you enjoyed the video.
And as per usual, YouTube recommends
that you watch this video, and
that you could
learn a lot from it. So please click
that and head over to that one.
I'll change your life there as well.